<?xml-stylesheet href="/rss.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dragons Not Included</title>
    <link>https://dragonsnotincluded.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Dragons Not Included</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>2020-2022, Dragons Not Included.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 18:48:45 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://dragonsnotincluded.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Chapter VI: Esmeralda</title>
        <link>https://dragonsnotincluded.github.io/posts/chapter-6/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://dragonsnotincluded.github.io/posts/chapter-6/</guid>
        <description>Dragons Not Included https://dragonsnotincluded.github.io/posts/chapter-6/ -&lt;p&gt;We are delighted to be able to inform the reader, that during the whole of
this scene, Gringoire and his piece had stood firm. His actors, spurred on
by him, had not ceased to spout his comedy, and he had not ceased to
listen to it. He had made up his mind about the tumult, and was determined
to proceed to the end, not giving up the hope of a return of attention on
the part of the public. This gleam of hope acquired fresh life, when he
saw Quasimodo, Coppenole, and the deafening escort of the pope of the
procession of fools quit the hall amid great uproar. The throng rushed
eagerly after them. “Good,” he said to himself, “there go all the
mischief-makers.” Unfortunately, all the mischief-makers constituted the
entire audience. In the twinkling of an eye, the grand hall was empty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To tell the truth, a few spectators still remained, some scattered, others
in groups around the pillars, women, old men, or children, who had had
enough of the uproar and tumult. Some scholars were still perched astride
of the window-sills, engaged in gazing into the Place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Well,” thought Gringoire, “here are still as many as are required to hear
the end of my mystery. They are few in number, but it is a choice
audience, a lettered audience.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An instant later, a symphony which had been intended to produce the
greatest effect on the arrival of the Virgin, was lacking. Gringoire
perceived that his music had been carried off by the procession of the
Pope of the Fools. “Skip it,” said he, stoically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He approached a group of bourgeois, who seemed to him to be discussing his
piece. This is the fragment of conversation which he caught,—&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You know, Master Cheneteau, the Hôtel de Navarre, which belonged to
Monsieur de Nemours?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Yes, opposite the Chapelle de Braque.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Well, the treasury has just let it to Guillaume Alixandre, historian, for
six hivres, eight sols, parisian, a year.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“How rents are going up!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Come,” said Gringoire to himself, with a sigh, “the others are
listening.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Comrades,” suddenly shouted one of the young scamps from the window, “La
Esmeralda! La Esmeralda in the Place!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This word produced a magical effect. Every one who was left in the hall
flew to the windows, climbing the walls in order to see, and repeating,
“La Esmeralda! La Esmeralda?” At the same time, a great sound of applause
was heard from without.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What’s the meaning of this, of the Esmeralda?” said Gringoire, wringing
his hands in despair. “Ah, good heavens! it seems to be the turn of the
windows now.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He returned towards the marble table, and saw that the representation had
been interrupted. It was precisely at the instant when Jupiter should have
appeared with his thunder. But Jupiter was standing motionless at the foot
of the stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Michel Giborne!” cried the irritated poet, “what are you doing there? Is
that your part? Come up!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Alas!” said Jupiter, “a scholar has just seized the ladder.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gringoire looked. It was but too true. All communication between his plot
and its solution was intercepted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The rascal,” he murmured. “And why did he take that ladder?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“In order to go and see the Esmeralda,” replied Jupiter piteously. “He
said, ‘Come, here’s a ladder that’s of no use!’ and he took it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the last blow. Gringoire received it with resignation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“May the devil fly away with you!” he said to the comedian, “and if I get
my pay, you shall receive yours.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then he beat a retreat, with drooping head, but the last in the field,
like a general who has fought well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And as he descended the winding stairs of the courts: “A fine rabble of
asses and dolts these Parisians!” he muttered between his teeth; “they
come to hear a mystery and don’t listen to it at all! They are engrossed
by every one, by Chopin Trouillefou, by the cardinal, by Coppenole, by
Quasimodo, by the devil! but by Madame the Virgin Mary, not at all. If I
had known, I’d have given you Virgin Mary; you ninnies! And I! to come to
see faces and behold only backs! to be a poet, and to reap the success of
an apothecary! It is true that Homerus begged through the Greek towns, and
that Naso died in exile among the Muscovites. But may the devil flay me if
I understand what they mean with their Esmeralda! What is that word, in
the first place?—‘tis Egyptian!”&lt;/p&gt;
- https://dragonsnotincluded.github.io/posts/chapter-6/ - 2020-2022, Dragons Not Included.</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Chapter I: The Grand Hall</title>
        <link>https://dragonsnotincluded.github.io/posts/chapter-1/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://dragonsnotincluded.github.io/posts/chapter-1/</guid>
        <description>Dragons Not Included https://dragonsnotincluded.github.io/posts/chapter-1/ -&lt;p&gt;Three hundred and forty-eight years, six months, and nineteen days ago
to-day, the Parisians awoke to the sound of all the bells in the triple
circuit of the city, the university, and the town ringing a full peal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sixth of January, 1482, is not, however, a day of which history has
preserved the memory. There was nothing notable in the event which thus
set the bells and the bourgeois of Paris in a ferment from early morning.
It was neither an assault by the Picards nor the Burgundians, nor a hunt
led along in procession, nor a revolt of scholars in the town of Laas, nor
an entry of “our much dread lord, monsieur the king,” nor even a pretty
hanging of male and female thieves by the courts of Paris. Neither was it
the arrival, so frequent in the fifteenth century, of some plumed and
bedizened embassy. It was barely two days since the last cavalcade of that
nature, that of the Flemish ambassadors charged with concluding the
marriage between the dauphin and Marguerite of Flanders, had made its
entry into Paris, to the great annoyance of M. le Cardinal de Bourbon,
who, for the sake of pleasing the king, had been obliged to assume an
amiable mien towards this whole rustic rabble of Flemish burgomasters, and
to regale them at his Hôtel de Bourbon, with a very “pretty morality,
allegorical satire, and farce,” while a driving rain drenched the
magnificent tapestries at his door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What put the “whole population of Paris in commotion,” as Jehan de Troyes
expresses it, on the sixth of January, was the double solemnity, united
from time immemorial, of the Epiphany and the Feast of Fools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On that day, there was to be a bonfire on the Place de Grève, a maypole at
the Chapelle de Braque, and a mystery at the Palais de Justice. It had
been cried, to the sound of the trumpet, the preceding evening at all the
cross roads, by the provost’s men, clad in handsome, short, sleeveless
coats of violet camelot, with large white crosses upon their breasts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the crowd of citizens, male and female, having closed their houses and
shops, thronged from every direction, at early morn, towards some one of
the three spots designated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each had made his choice; one, the bonfire; another, the maypole; another,
the mystery play. It must be stated, in honor of the good sense of the
loungers of Paris, that the greater part of this crowd directed their
steps towards the bonfire, which was quite in season, or towards the
mystery play, which was to be presented in the grand hall of the Palais de
Justice (the courts of law), which was well roofed and walled; and that
the curious left the poor, scantily flowered maypole to shiver all alone
beneath the sky of January, in the cemetery of the Chapel of Braque.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The populace thronged the avenues of the law courts in particular, because
they knew that the Flemish ambassadors, who had arrived two days
previously, intended to be present at the representation of the mystery,
and at the election of the Pope of the Fools, which was also to take place
in the grand hall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was no easy matter on that day, to force one’s way into that grand
hall, although it was then reputed to be the largest covered enclosure in
the world (it is true that Sauval had not yet measured the grand hall of
the Château of Montargis). The palace place, encumbered with people,
offered to the curious gazers at the windows the aspect of a sea; into
which five or six streets, like so many mouths of rivers, discharged every
moment fresh floods of heads. The waves of this crowd, augmented
incessantly, dashed against the angles of the houses which projected here
and there, like so many promontories, into the irregular basin of the
place. In the centre of the lofty Gothic* façade of the palace, the grand
staircase, incessantly ascended and descended by a double current, which,
after parting on the intermediate landing-place, flowed in broad waves
along its lateral slopes,—the grand staircase, I say, trickled
incessantly into the place, like a cascade into a lake. The cries, the
laughter, the trampling of those thousands of feet, produced a great noise
and a great clamor. From time to time, this noise and clamor redoubled;
the current which drove the crowd towards the grand staircase flowed
backwards, became troubled, formed whirlpools. This was produced by the
buffet of an archer, or the horse of one of the provost’s sergeants, which
kicked to restore order; an admirable tradition which the provostship has
bequeathed to the constablery, the constablery to the &lt;em&gt;maréchaussée&lt;/em&gt;,
the &lt;em&gt;maréchaussée&lt;/em&gt; to our &lt;em&gt;gendarmeri&lt;/em&gt; of Paris.&lt;/p&gt;
- https://dragonsnotincluded.github.io/posts/chapter-1/ - 2020-2022, Dragons Not Included.</description>
        </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss> 